<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tips on Najam Sikander Awan</title>
    <link>https://najamawans.com/categories/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tips on Najam Sikander Awan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 22:23:21 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://najamawans.com/categories/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>fetch public tweets of any user using jQuery</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-05-03-fetch-public-tweets-of-any-user-using-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-05-03-fetch-public-tweets-of-any-user-using-jquery/</guid>
      <description>I have been asked by many friends how to load tweets of any user using jQuery I have put some time and found two ways to do that using jQuery.
Twitter Timeline API following is the code to get public tweets of any user using javascript and twitter timeline api
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 $.ajax({ type : &amp;#39;GET&amp;#39;, dataType : &amp;#39;jsonp&amp;#39;, url : &amp;#39;http://api.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB Setup On Windows 8</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-10-22-mongodb-setup-on-windows-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-10-22-mongodb-setup-on-windows-8/</guid>
      <description>I am very much into learning new tools and burning hours of my life trying to figure them out. To track whats new on development horizon and technology I tend to keep my eyes on sessions, conferences, blogs and screen-casts.
In past few days I wanted to explore no-sql options two in particular RavenDB and MongoDB. I have successfully completed the environment setup for raven but didn&amp;rsquo;t use it in any project until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MVC3 Scaffolding Commands</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-05-03-mvc3-scafolding-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-05-03-mvc3-scafolding-commands/</guid>
      <description>I had a freelance project that I have decided to do in MVC3 and to found following scaffolding commands very useful to get my Context, repository, controller, controller and views in PM console inside visual studio
1 2 3 4 5 Scaffold DbContext -Project CRS.Domain Service Concrete.CRSContext Scaffold Repository -ModelType Attachment -DbContextType BigApp.Domain.Concrete.BigAppContext -force Scaffold Controller -ModelType BigApp.Domain.Entities.Project -ControllerName Projects -DbContextType BigApp.Domain.Concrete.BigAppContext -Repository -NoChildItems -Force Scaffold Controller -ModelType CRS.Domain.Entities.Service -ControllerName Services -DbContextType CRS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing jQuery code via YUI Test</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-05-03-testing-jquery-code-via-yui-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2013-05-03-testing-jquery-code-via-yui-test/</guid>
      <description>The term TDD is not new to me I heard it quite often but never took time to go into details until last few days. I have been checking stuff from YUI team and liked their YUI test framework for now ,but in future i might switch to qUint (jquery testing framework) as I am big fan of jQuery and using it daily.
There are different version of YUI like 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Diet Plan - first step to object oriented css</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2010-12-03-css-diet-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2010-12-03-css-diet-plan/</guid>
      <description>I was wondering how to count the rules of my style sheets after little googling i discovered two ways one is through vim and second is through a command line tool called grep.
If you are a vim user and your css file is loaded into vim in command mode enter following command
output will be the number of type font-size is used in your css file.
for grep open your command line and enter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Overflow benefit</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2010-12-08-css-overflow-benefit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2010-12-08-css-overflow-benefit/</guid>
      <description>I read this article http://bit.ly/16pqBm and find out the power of overflow that is when you set it to a value it creates a new block formatting context in simple word that means non floated element’s content will not flow around the floated element instead will get narrower.
PS. Width should not be mentioned for non floated content so it can get narrower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Running Jquery Version</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2010-12-06-get-running-jquery-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2010-12-06-get-running-jquery-version/</guid>
      <description>Few weeks back I came across a page that has multiple jquery versions referenced in it and I had no idea which jquery version is actually running. So after little bit of googling I find following solution.
//Returns &amp;ldquo;1.3.1&amp;rdquo; jQuery.fn.jquery;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlight your code with wordpress</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2009-02-03-highlight-your-code-with-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2009-02-03-highlight-your-code-with-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys, Today I have installed a new wordpress plugin called &amp;ldquo;Code Snippet&amp;rdquo; and it support code highlight for many languages try this out you would love it. Download it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Core6 spoofing mac address</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-02-11-testing-fedora-core6-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-02-11-testing-fedora-core6-live/</guid>
      <description>hi
Guyz i am writing this post while using fedora core 6 live cd and it took 2 hours to make internet working on this live distro.
I have acer 1642ZNWLCi with 1.7 ghz, 512 mb, and 60 gb HDD. I have a cabel connection and my cabel operator is keepig record of my mac address and only one mac address is allowed so to run internet on all my pc i have to spoof mac addresss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oh God Hd audio driver for linux</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-02-13-oh-god-hd-audio-driver-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-02-13-oh-god-hd-audio-driver-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>hi guyz;
Well after solving problem for my lan card through mac spoofing next problem that I want to solve now is making sound work on my acer laptop while running fedore core 6 live cd.
Now as i inspect my hardware i get to know that i have a realtek sound card that has hd audio codec Alc 883 now.
to check if your hardware is detected by linux or not you have to run following command in shell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realtek HD sound card working</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-02-20-realtek-hd-sound-card-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-02-20-realtek-hd-sound-card-working/</guid>
      <description>Hi guyz
My sound card working now after installing latest Alsa driver, Lib and Utils.
Compile alsa-driver like this:
1 2 3 ./configure --with-cards=hda-intel make make install and alsa-lib and alsa-util in this order like this:
1 2 3 ./configure make make install Reboot and there you go!
Regards Najam Sikander Awan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make custom spray for CS</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-01-06-how-to-use-custom-spray-in-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2006 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2007-01-06-how-to-use-custom-spray-in-cs/</guid>
      <description>hi
its very easy to use custome sprays in counter strike just follow all the steps given below
download spray file with extension wad
then rename it to tempdecal.wad
now i have cs 1.6
goto Counter-Strike\cstrike and paste wad file now start game goto options select srap apply it and start playing and during play press T to spray. Bye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed Up Firfox</title>
      <link>https://najamawans.com/posts/2005-12-01-speed-up-firfox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2005 22:23:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://najamawans.com/posts/2005-12-01-speed-up-firfox/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
